Eduardo Faccin Vernier

I hold a joint PhD degree from the universities of Groningen and Rio Grande do Sul for my research on visualization methods for hierarchical and high-dimensional data. I focused on dynamic treemaps and dynamic projection techniques, creating comprehensive evaluations, developing state-of-the-art methods, and applying these in the clinical context of hyperkinetic movement disorders.

+31 651731257 Utrecht, Netherlands efvernier@gmail.com eduardovernier.github.io Google Scholar

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Programs — Junior Data Scientist — Amsterdam

October 2021 - (current) - mlprograms.com

Design, implementation, and production of machine learning models for the insurance and finance sectors.

Isobar IWS Brazil — Intern Android Developer — Porto Alegre

September 2016 - February 2017 - isobar.com

Development of prototype applications for Android (Java).

SAP Labs Latin America — Intern Web Developer — São Leopoldo

January 2014 - March 2014 - sap.com

Development of a web prototype for the management of Randon's Vehicle Testing Facilities using Javascript and the SAPUI5 framework.

EDUCATION

Joint PhD in Computer Science — University of Groningen (RuG) and Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul (UFRGS)

August 2017 - October 2021

- Thesis: "Visualization of Dynamic Multidimensional and Hierarchical Datasets"
- Course organization and teaching experience
- Published and presented at high profile conferences and journals
- 4+ years experience with Python, pandas, numpy, matplotlib, and ML libraries

Master in Computer Science — Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul March 2017 - August 2017 (didn't finish, upgraded to PhD program after 6 months)

Branetec Exchange Program — University of Groningen

August 2015 - July 2016

Bachelor Degree in Computer Science— Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul — March 2012 - December 2016

PEER-REVIEWED ARTICLES (all PDFs and extras on personal website)

Guided Stable Dynamic Projections

Proc. EuroVis, Zurich, Switzerland (Computer Graphics Forum) - 2021

Quantitative Evaluation of Time-Dependent Multidimensional **Projection Techniques**

Proc. EuroVis, Norrköping, Sweden (Computer Graphics Forum) - 2020

Quantitative Comparison of Time-Dependent Treemaps

Proc. EuroVis, Norrköping, Sweden (Computer Graphics Forum) - 2020

Selecting and Sharing Multidimensional Projection Algorithms: A

Practical View Proc. VISGAP, Norrköping, Sweden - 2020

A Stable Greedy Insertion Treemap Algorithm for Software Evolution Visualization Proc. SIBGRAPI, Foz do Iguaçu, Brazil - 2018

Distinguished paper award

Quantitative Comparison of Dynamic Treemaps for Software Evolution Visualization Proc. VISSOFT, Madrid, Spain - 2018

Best poster award.

Quantitative Comparison of Treemap Techniques for

Time-Dependent Hierarchies Proc. EuroVis, Barcelona, Spain - 2017

Metric Evolution Maps: Multidimensional Attribute-driven

Exploration of Software Repositories Proc. VMV, Bayreuth, Germany - 2016

LANGUAGES Portuguese - Native Spanish - Intermediate English - Fluent Dutch - Basic

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

NEMO Project (RuG/UMCG/Ziuz)

September 2020 - October 2021

Collaboration in a large-scale project with teams of medical and machine learning experts to develop classifiers and gain insight into hyperkinetic movement disorders.

Scientific Visualization and Computer Graphics Group (RuG)

November 2015 - July 2016 and June 2017 - July 2017

Development of temporal and high dimensional data visualization techniques applied to understanding software quality metrics evolution in open source projects.

Basin Modeling Lab (UFRGS)

May 2014 - December 2014

Development of methodologies and tools for the forecast and response to natural catastrophes in collaboration with IEEE SIGHT and Civil Defence RS. Focus on image processing in C++ and high definition large area mosaicing of aerial photography.

PET Computação Group (UFRGS)

October 2012 - January 2014

Instructor on multiple editions of Arduino and C Language courses; Collaborator on the development of small-scale robotics projects.

OTHER PROJECTS

TC de Uithof - Technical committee 2020 - 2021 - Development of tennis training enrolment and control systems. Built telegram bots hosted at AWS that notify members of freed training spots in real-time with 300+ subscriptions.

Bike de Boa – Mobile Developer

2017 - 2019 - Open source project that maps the bike parking infrastructure in Brazil with 200k+ visits.

bikedeboa.com.br